<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Selfhosted on Adib.notes</title>
    <link>/tags/selfhosted/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Selfhosted on Adib.notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/selfhosted/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Simple Backup with Borgmatic</title>
      <link>/posts/20221001-backup-with-borgmatic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/20221001-backup-with-borgmatic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a self-hosted person, I own a VPS and have installed some applications that I use in my day-to-day activities.&#xA;Those apps (like chat server, using &lt;a href=&#34;https://matrix.org/&#34;&gt;Matrix&lt;/a&gt;) are becoming a part of my life, and losing the data that&amp;rsquo;s been there will be disastrous for me.&#xA;Hence, backup is a must thing to do.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Doing backup isn&amp;rsquo;t that hard, especially if we use the right tools.&#xA;For the past few years, I&amp;rsquo;ve been using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.borgbackup.org/&#34;&gt;borg&lt;/a&gt; as a tool for doing backup of all my computer-related data. It&amp;rsquo;s a simple and easy-to-use tool. And combine with &lt;a href=&#34;https://torsion.org/borgmatic/&#34;&gt;borgmatic&lt;/a&gt;, a program on top of borg to make the backup process even easier, backing up a whole data, both from a database and from the file, is as simple as running one command. Borgmatic use a configuration file to do the whole process. Here is my simple configuration that I used on regular basis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Installing libolm From Source</title>
      <link>/posts/08-installing-libolm-from-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/08-installing-libolm-from-source/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I stumble upon this great tool called &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/8go/matrix-commander&#34;&gt;matrix-commander&lt;/a&gt; that I think is the simplest way to programmatically interact with your &lt;a href=&#34;https://matrix.org/&#34;&gt;Matrix&lt;/a&gt; server.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;m using these tools in order to send notifications from my server to my matrix room whenever something interesting happens (i.e when my backup is done, or when someone login to my server).&#xA;It is based on matrix-nio, and only a large single file python.&#xA;But I found one of the dependencies, &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.matrix.org/matrix-org/olm&#34;&gt;libolm&lt;/a&gt;, is quite difficult to install (especially in my raspberry pi).&#xA;They do have a package in pip, but it&amp;rsquo;s only for python version 2.&#xA;Here is what I do to build this library from source.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
