<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Adib.notes</title>
    <link>/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Adib.notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AI Models that Runs Locally</title>
      <link>/posts/20230521-local-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/20230521-local-ai/</guid>
      <description>The rise of ChatGPT and other large language models is pretty fascinating in the past few months.
New models are being published with larger model sizes and data, claiming to make an improvement from before.
Apart from some serious debate on the potential danger of the technology, it surely opens new ways for us to do the things we used to do.
Since some models are too expensive to run just for fun, I look and tried several models that could be run locally on my computer so I could build something interesting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Backup with Borgmatic</title>
      <link>/posts/20221001-backup-with-borgmatic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/20221001-backup-with-borgmatic/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a self-hosted person, I own a VPS and have installed some applications that I use in my day-to-day activities. Those apps (like chat server, using Matrix) are becoming a part of my life, and losing the data that&amp;rsquo;s been there will be disastrous for me. Hence, backup is a must thing to do.
Doing backup isn&amp;rsquo;t that hard, especially if we use the right tools. For the past few years, I&amp;rsquo;ve been using borg as a tool for doing backup of all my computer-related data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Significance Test</title>
      <link>/posts/20220620-significance-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/20220620-significance-test/</guid>
      <description>The main idea is we need to know whether this distribution is more likely to happen from another distribution with a level of p. So w need three things:
The first distribution (base) and its parameter The second distribution (comparator) and its parameter A limit/threshold for which we could safely say this is different. The Z - Test The T-test is for small use case ≤ 30, whereas the z-test is for the normal case.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Modified Files Within Two Snapshot</title>
      <link>/posts/20220602-get-modified-files-within-two-snapshot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/20220602-get-modified-files-within-two-snapshot/</guid>
      <description>To make my blogging habit a little bit easier, I create a tool to easily convert my jupyter notebooks to markdown that could be parsed into Hugo, called pynote2mds3 that use nbconvert to convert and upload any image into S3. However, I soon find out that I need to manually run this command for each of my new posts and I kind of looking for a way to automate that. The solution is using make.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing libolm From Source</title>
      <link>/posts/08-installing-libolm-from-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/08-installing-libolm-from-source/</guid>
      <description>I stumble upon this great tool called matrix-commander that I think is the simplest way to programmatically interact with your Matrix server. I&amp;rsquo;m using these tools in order to send notifications from my server to my matrix room whenever something interesting happens (i.e when my backup is done, or when someone login to my server). It is based on matrix-nio, and only a large single file python. But I found one of the dependencies, libolm, is quite difficult to install (especially in my raspberry pi).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shortcut to Capture Ideas</title>
      <link>/posts/shortcut_text/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/shortcut_text/</guid>
      <description>One common theme from the majority of productivity articles/books that I read is to never let use your brain to store information. Use it to generate new ideas, to solve a problem, to think.
But here is the thing: Sometimes when you are in a state of deep work, focusing on a task at hand, you might suddenly remember other tasks that you need to do later, or you might get an idea for other things that might not be related to your current task.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux VPN via PPTP dari Terminal</title>
      <link>/posts/oldpost/linux-vpn-via-pptp-dari-terminal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/oldpost/linux-vpn-via-pptp-dari-terminal/</guid>
      <description>Sebagai salah satu cara untuk terhubung dengan resource yang ada di kantor ketika kita berada diluar (remote) adalah dengan menggunakan VPN. Ada beberapa jenis VPN, seperti openvpn dan pptp. Kali ini saya akan membahas proses koneksi VPN menggunakan PPTP di linux melalui command line.
Langkahnya adalah :
Memeriksa file yang dibutuhkan Membuat file konfigurasi Membuat koneksi Set default routing 1. Requirements Untuk dapat terhubung melalui VPN PPTP, ada 3 hal yang harus dimiliki, yakni:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
