<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Project on Adib.notes</title>
    <link>/tags/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Project on Adib.notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Simple Daily Journal Prompt</title>
      <link>/project/03_journal_prompt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/03_journal_prompt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past few years, I&amp;rsquo;ve developed a daily writing habit in my note-taking apps (I&amp;rsquo;m currently using Notion, having migrated from Evernote a few months ago). At first, I just write my daily feeling, what negative or positive emotions I currently feel, and the source of them. It helps me meditate on my life. Sometimes I even come up with a good quote or self-advice.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But writing about feeling alone might be boring sometimes, so I started to look for something different. I come up with a daily prompt, which is a set of questions that you could pick randomly each day and start exploring answers from that.&#xA;It&amp;rsquo;s super fun for me since I might spend the day wandering about the question. It&amp;rsquo;s not the question itself, but rather where the question takes me. Sometimes it takes me to the future, asking about my ideal life, sometime in the past, asking about my painful memory. It&amp;rsquo;s random every day, so I could learn a few things every day.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Get Modified Files Within Two Snapshot</title>
      <link>/posts/20220602-get-modified-files-within-two-snapshot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/20220602-get-modified-files-within-two-snapshot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To make my blogging habit a little bit easier, I create a tool to easily convert my jupyter notebooks to markdown that could be parsed into &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;, called &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/adibPr/pynote2mds3/&#34;&gt;pynote2mds3&lt;/a&gt; that use &lt;code&gt;nbconvert&lt;/code&gt; to convert and upload any image into S3. However, I soon find out that I need to manually run this command for each of my new posts and I kind of looking for a way to automate that. The solution is using &lt;code&gt;make&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Jupyter notebook - S3 Blogging Platform</title>
      <link>/project/02_jupyter_gdrive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/02_jupyter_gdrive/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Markdown is a good format to write almost anything. But we as a data scientist, use Jupyter Notebook, a lot. We could do a very rapid experiment, with plot, data frame, etc. This makes me wonder, is it possible to turn a jupyter notes into a blog post? I actually try to do this at my current company, to create some sort of knowledge management platform for our research team.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Simple Hugo Theme </title>
      <link>/project/01_site/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/01_site/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This website is built using hand crafted theme as a medium for me to learn &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; theming.&#xA;It&amp;rsquo;s not that beauty since I&amp;rsquo;m not a web developer, but I&amp;rsquo;ve learned so much about hugo and CSS/HTML in general.&#xA;You can find the code in &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/adibPr/adibpr.theme&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
